<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hugo on </title>
    <link>https://lukeorth.com/tags/hugo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hugo on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 05:32:16 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lukeorth.com/tags/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Starting a Blog - take three</title>
      <link>https://lukeorth.com/posts/starting-with-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 05:32:16 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lukeorth.com/posts/starting-with-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Several years ago, I started a blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time, I was a college sophomore looking for internship opportunities.  I had just finished my second programming class and had zero experience outside the classroom.  The blog was my gambit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My web development skills were nil (or null if you prefer), but I knew enough to understand that my C++ coursework wouldn&amp;rsquo;t help.  After some quick research, I learned that websites are just a combination of HTML, CSS, and something called jQuery (&lt;em&gt;where would we be without Quora?&lt;/em&gt;).  With this naive understanding, I forged ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I copied some boilerplate HTML from W3Schools, plagiarized bits of CSS from StackOverflow, and gave up on jQuery (too much hassle).  After a couple of weeks, it was finished.  I purchased a domain name, set up hosting for $13 a month, and added the URL to my resume.  Now it was time to add some content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I knew that my posts would eventually need to be formatted in HTML, I feared this constraint might hamper my &amp;ldquo;creative juices.&amp;rdquo;  To protect my creativity, I typed my posts in a Word document and converted them to HTML once finished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can imagine, this was tedious work.  Every section became a &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, every paragraph became a &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag, every link became an &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;a&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag, and so on.  Mustering the drive to write a blog post is hard enough.  Turning it into a two-step process was asinine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I completed just two posts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
